Guide to the Local Newspapers on Microfilm Collection BCMS.0028
Brooklyn Collection
- Mill Basin Civic News, 1940-1985; 2 Reels (Bin 28)
  Published monthly by the Mill Basin Civic Association, Mill Basin Civic News focuses on the neighborhoods of Mill Basin, Kingslawn, and Flatlands. The paper provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, clubs and organizations, community events, sports, and religion. Early issues of the paper do not contain birth announcements, wedding announcements, or death announcements; however, these items appear in some later issues. Advertisements appear throughout.
- New York Beacon, 1994-1995; 1 Reels (Bin 28)
  The New York Beacon provides city-wide coverage of African-American news and issues in business, politics, education, community events, arts, culture, religion and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. A community calendar highlighting events in the African-American community regular appears. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- New York & Brooklyn Daily, 1963-1969; 43 Reels (Bin 28, Bin 29, Bin 37)
  The New York and Brooklyn Daily provides national, international, and city-wide news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- New York Recorder, 1956-1987; 29 Reels
  The New York Recorder provides city-wide coverage of African-American news and issues in business, politics, education, community events, arts, culture, religion and entertainment. Birth announcements and wedding announcements do not appear in the paper. Obituaries and death notices only appear for prominent Brooklynites. Regularly appearing columns include: "Teenagers Report;" "Greek Notes," which provides news of clubs and fraternal orders; and "About Our Churches." An illustrated poetry page appears in later issues. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- New York World Telegram and The Sun, 1959-1965; 30 Reels
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Bay Ridge and Canarsie, the New York World Telegram and the Sun provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. National and international news coverage is also provided. Birth announcements and wedding announcements occasionally appear in a column called "Brooklyn Society." Obituaries regularly appear in the paper. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- The Newspaper, 1988-1989; 1 Reels (Bin 29)
  Largely focusing on the areas of Carroll Gardens, Cobble Hill, Brooklyn Heights, Boerum Hill, Red Hook, and Park Slope, the Brooklyn Paper--Carroll Gardens and Cobble Hill, provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, arts, culture, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. A regularly appearing section called, "Merchant Profiles" provides photographs and descriptions of many local businesses. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout. (See also: Brooklyn Paper—Carroll Gardens, Cobble Hill & Carroll Gardens/Cobble Hill Courier.)
- Norden, 1979-1994; 6 Reels (Bin 29)
  Norden is a Finnish-language newspaper providing coverage of news and events related to New York City's Finnish population. Some articles appear in English. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Nordisk Tidende, 1956-1997; 37 Reels (Bin 29, Bin 30)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Bay Ridge, Nordisk Tidende provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Articles in early issues of the paper are primarily written in Norwegian, with later issues being equally split between English and Norwegian. National, international, and local news is all covered. Wedding and engagement announcements occasionally appear. Obituaries do not appear in the paper. Poems and recipes are regularly published as are profiles of local businesses. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- North Brooklyn News, August 1980 - April 1981; 2 Reels (Bin 30)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Bushwick, Bedford-Stuyvesant, Greenpoint, Williamsburg, Fort Green, Clinton Hill, and Downtown Brooklyn, the North Brooklyn News provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Extensive coverage is given to local politics, with numerous photographs of community leaders appearing regularly in the paper. Coverage of events at local organizations such as the Ridgewood-Bushwick Senior Citizens Center, the Brooklyn Rotary Club, and the Williamsburg Luncheon Club frequently appear. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Park Slope Home Reporter and Sunset News, 1964-1981; 31 Reels (Bin 30, Bin 31)
  Largely focusing on the Park Slope neighborhood, the Park Slope Home Reporter and Sunset News provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Wedding announcements occasionally appear often accompanied by photographs. Notices of military deployments regularly appear as do reviews of local restaurants. Extensive coverage is also given to the opening of the Verrazano-Narrows bridge. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Park Slope Paper, 1985-1998; 6 Reels (Bin 31)
  Largely focusing on Park Slope and the surrounding neighborhoods, the Park Slope Paper provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. The paper features a weekly events guide, a Brooklyn business page, and a "Wine and Dine" section. Advertisements and obituaries do not appear in the paper.
- The Phoenix, 1972-1997; 26 Reels (Bin 31)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Brooklyn Heights, Boerum Hill, Carroll Gardens, and Cobble Hill, The Phoenix provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, religion, arts, culture, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Regular and extensive coverage is given to local politics. Brownstone culture—including neighborhood guides, real estate news, and renovation tips—is also consistently covered. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Prospect Press, 1982-1987; 5 Reels (Bin 32)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Park Slope, Sunset Park, Kensington, and Windsor Terrace, the Prospect Press provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, and entertainment. Birth announcements and wedding announcements do not appear in the paper. Obituaries for prominent Brooklynites occasionally appear. In-depth profiles of Park Slope residents—from Vietnamese immigrants to psychics—regularly appear in the paper. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- The Record and Advertiser, 1961-1969; 2 Reels (Bin 32)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of East New York, Cypress Hills, and Highland Park, The Record and Advertiser provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, religion, arts, culture, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Notices of military deployments regularly appear. Regularly published columns include "Local Church Activities" and "Women's Page." Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Ridgewood Times, 1956-1989; 62 Reels (Bin 32)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Ridgewood, Maspeth, Woodhaven, and Glendale, the Ridgewood Times provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, religion, arts, culture, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries all regularly appear in the paper. Scouting news, for both Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts, is also regularly covered. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Times Newsweekly, 1989-1998; 45 Reels (Bin 33)
  Established in 1908 as the Ridgewood Times, Times Newsweekly provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, religion, arts, culture, sports, and entertainment. The neighborhoods of Ridgewood, Maspeth, Woodhaven, and Glendale are all covered. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries all regularly appear in the paper. Scouting news, for both Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts, is also regularly covered. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- The Township, 1970-1977; 1 Reels (Bin 34)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Boerum Hill, Brooklyn Heights, and Cobble Hill, The Township provides local news coverage of business, politics, and community events. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. The paper, published by the Brooklyn Heights Citizens for Local Democracy, is primarily concerned with city planning issues, political activism, citizen's rights issues, and community politics. Advertisements, photographs, comics, and illustrations appear throughout.
- Up the Slope, 1977-1978; 1 Reels (Bin 34)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Park Slope, Up the Slope provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, religion, arts, culture, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Numerous articles concerning the "red-lining" issue in Park Slope appear. Columns in Spanish are regularly published, as are poems contributed by local residents. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Vienybe, 1960-1984; 7 Reels (Bin 36)
  Vienybe is a Lithuanian language newspaper providing coverage of news and events related to New York City's Lithuanian population. International as well as local news is regularly covered. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- The Voice, 1885-1888; 2 Reels (Bin 35)
  A paper devoted to furthering the cause of the temperance movement, The Voice provides city-wide news coverage of all relevant issues and events. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Advertisements and illustrations appear throughout.
- The Weekly Chat [The Chat], 1903-1929; 125 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Bushwick and the surrounding area, The Weekly Chat provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, religion, arts, culture, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements occasionally appear, with births at Williamsburg Maternity Hospital being regularly published. Early issues of the paper occasionally include wedding announcements and obituaries while later issues include them on a regular basis. Graduation announcements from local schools also appear regularly. A regularly appearing "Chat" column provides extensive coverage of the comings and goings of local residents—highlighting such things as vacations, meetings, condolences, and surprise birthday parties. A Brooklyn theater guide is also regularly published covering performances at such theaters as: the Decatur, the Majestic, the Rialto, the Halsey, and Loew's, to name just a few. Later issues of the paper also include a separate section devoted to the neighborhoods of Ridgewood, Glendale, Middle Village, and Maspeth. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Williamsburg Daily Gazette, 1850; 1 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Williamsburg, the Williamsburg Gazette publishes brief articles covering events of local interest. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Editorials and opinion pieces appear regularly. Advertisements appear throughout.
- Williamsburg Daily Times, 1848-1854; 8 Reels (Bin 36)
  Largely focusing on the area of Williamsburg, the Williamsburg Daily Times consists of advertisements and brief local news items. Birth notices do not appear in the paper. Marriage and death notices occasionally appear. Illustrations do not appear in the paper.
- Williamsburg Gazette and Long Island Advertiser, 1835-1838, 1845-1847; 2 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Williamsburg, the Williamsburg Gazette and Long Island Advertiser publishes brief articles covering events of local interest. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Editorials and opinion pieces appear regularly. Advertisements appear throughout.
- Williamsburg News, 1952-1976; 15 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers, Bin 37)
  Issues up to 1965 are available digitally on Brooklyn Newsstand. That content is also available via your or your library's paid subscription to Newspapers.com.
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Williamsburg, Greenpoint, Bushwick, and East New York, the Williamsburg News provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, religion, arts, culture, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.